today I'd like to talk with you about
open innovation open innovation is a set
of practices for engaging with large
numbers of people with very diverse
perspectives and knowledge sets to solve
previously intractable problems now one
definition of open innovation is
relative to a firm or a company which is
that traditionally innovation has
happened within the boundaries of the
company it's called closed or internal
innovation and open innovation is where
new ideas are being developed or new
services and technologies are being
created in partnership with other
individuals and organizations outside of
the boundaries of the firm so what makes
open innovation different is that it's
possible to have the crowd solve
problems that only the crowd can solve
for example if there is a large number
of people going to an e-commerce site
such as ebay or amazon com and they
don't know if they can trust buyers and
sellers then that's something that
individuals aren't able to solve on
their own but using an internal rating
system where people who have bought from
a previous owner in the past variable to
solve the problem of trust through this
internal rating system so the collective
activities or the aggregate of
activities of many individuals creates a
robust measure of trustworthiness for
people who are sellers when there's a
high level of anonymity people don't
know who the buyers are or who the
sellers are so this is an example of the
crowd solving a problem through smart
design of the infrastructure for
information is exchanged within a system
similarly a corporation like a
technology firm can apply the same
principles of open engagement and
collaboration and smart design of
interaction architecture to cultivate
intelligence at a collective level now
open innovation is the set of practices
for doing this effectively